Gertrude Berg Papers
Gertrude Berg Papers
- Radio and T.V. Scripts, Total 1001
  - Special subjects, miscellaneous
    - Interviews
      - Listen America, Nov. 23, 1941; Jan. 4, 1942,; May 26, 1944 (Box 51)
      - Margaret Arlen Show, May 26, 1944; Oct. 14, 1949 (Box 51)
      - Nellie Revell Show, Mar. 19, (no year) (Box 51)
      - Paul Whiteman Record Club, April 6, 1948 (Box 51)
      - Star Dust, May 3, 1931; Mar. 4, 1934,; May 26, 1940 (Box 51)
      - With G. Berg, re: move "The Goldbergs" (Box 51)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 51)
    - Movies
      - "Main Street to Broadway", scripts (Box 51)
      - "Make a Wish", final shooting script (Box 51)
    - Plays, stage
      - "The Goldbergs", original mss. & revision; 3 folders (Box 52)
      - "Majority of One", 1959-1960; 3 folders (Box 52)
    - Plays, summer stock
      - "Arsenic and Old Lace", 1956 (Box 52)
      - "Matchmaker", 1957; 2 folders (Box 52)
      - "Solid Gold Cadillac", 1956 (Box 52)
    - Plays, television
      - Alcoa Hour- "Paris and Mrs. Perlman", Apr. 26, 1956 (Box 52)
      - Matinee Theatre- "Golden Door", June 4, 1957 (Box 52)
      - The Play of the Week - "The World of Sholom Aleichem", Nov. 30, 1959 (Box 52)
      - United States Steel Hour
        - "Morning Star", Oct. 5, 1952; Feb. 17, 1954; radio script also (Box 52)
        - "Six o'Clock Call", Jan. 15, 1955 (Box 52)
        - "Trouble-In-Law", Apr. 22, 1959 (Box 53)
    - Scripts, selected
      - Easter scripts, 1938-1944 (Box 53)
      - Selected Goldberg scripts, 1942-1945 (Box 53)
      - Yum Kippur, 1941-1954 (Box 53)
    - Scripts, special occasions
      - Allied Jewish Appeal, Philadelphia, undated (Box 53)
      - "CARE" Hannukkah Show, Dec. 4, 1950 (Box 53)
      - Elsa Maxwell Party, undated (Box 53)
      - "The Four Seasons" Walter Slezack, undated (Box 53)
      - G-Day Rally, Cleveland, Ohio, Apr. 9, 1951 (Box 53)
      - Goldberg's 20th Anniversary, undated (Box 53)
      - "Here Comes Axel" (Box 53)
      - National Council of Jewish Women Award, San Francisco, undated (Box 53)
      - Promotional & spot announcements (Box 53)
      - Stop the Music, 1950 (Box 53)
      - Uncle Schnozzle (Box 53)
      - War Bonds & Loans, 1943-1944 (Box 53)
      - Synopsis & outlines, 1937-1945; 3 folders (Box 53)
      - Vaudeville Act-"The Goldbergs", undated (Box 53)
- Published materials
  - Academy, Apr. 1952 (Box 54)
  - Achievement, May 1951 (Box 54)
  - The Advertiser, Jan. 1936 (Box 54)
  - Advertising Agency and Advertising and Sailing, June, 1948 (Box 54)
  - America, Mar. 7, 1954 (Box 54)
  - The American Magazine, Nov. 1941; Dec. 1952 (2) (Box 54)
  - The American Hebrew, Sept. 4, 1942 (2); Sept. 17, 1943,; Oct. 8, 1943 (Box 54)
  - American Hebrew and Jewish Tribune, Oct. 21, 1932 (Box 54)
  - The Billboard, Oct. 20, 1934 (Box 54)
  - Commentary, Apr. 1956 (Box 54)
  - Congress Weekly (2), Mar. 5, 1951 (Box 54)
  - Congress Weekly, Mar. 1951; Overseas edition (Box 54)
  - Coronet (2), Feb. 1951 (Box 54)
  - Cosmopolitan (2), May 1959 (Box 54)
  - Cue, Aug. 7, 1943; May 21, 1949,; Nov. 11, 1950 (2),; Jan. 6, 1951,; Mar. 10, 1951,; Sept. 29, 1951 (2),; Feb. 23, 1952,; July 4, 1953,; July 11, 1953 (2),; Sept. 5, 1953,; Apr. 17, 1954,; May 8, 1954,; Feb. 28, 1959; 2 folders (Box 54)
  - The Dumont Tele-Centre, June 14, 1954 (Oversize 19)
  - Everywoman's, Feb. 1945 (Box 54)
  - Fame, 1942; 1943,; 1950; 3 folders (Box 54)
  - Flair, Dec. 1950; Jan. 1951 (Box 54)
  - Furniture Age, Mar. 1951 (Oversize 19)
  - Glamour (2), Feb. 1951 (Box 54)
  - Good Housekeeping, Jan. 1951 (Box 54)
  - Gotham Life, Feb. 21, 1959 (Box 54)
  - Holiday, Apr. 1955 (Oversize 19)
  - Hollywood Quarterly, Jan. 1946 (Box 54)
  - The Jewish Forum, Mar. 1959 (Box 54)
  - The Jewish Tribune, Oct. 10, 1930 (Box 54)
  - The Jewish Veteran, Mar. 1944 (Box 54)
  - The Journal of Living, Oct. 1943 (2); Apr. 1950 (Box 54)
  - Leisure Time, Aug. 2, 1953 (2); Dec. 13, 1953 (Box 54)
  - Life, Dec. 1, 1947; Apr. 25, 1949 (2),; Mar. 9, 1959 (2); 3 folders (Box 54)
  - Look, Apr. 26, 1949; Feb. 13, 1951 (2),; Feb. 27, 1951 (2),; Mar. 1, 1960 (2); 3 folders (Box 54)
  - McCalls (2), Oct. 1955 (Box 55)
  - Majority of One, undated (Box 55)
  - Mayfair (2), summer issue 1951 (Box 55)
  - The Microphone, Sept. 27, 1935 (Box 55)
  - The Nation, Mar. 7, 1959 (Box 55)
  - The National Jewish Monthly, Jan. 1955 (Box 55)
  - National Parent-Teacher, June 1950 (Box 55)
  - Newsweek, Apr. 11, 1954; Jan. 15, 1951,; Mar. 2, 1959 (Box 55)
  - The New Yorker, Feb. 28, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Page One, 1951; 1954 (Box 55)
  - Panorama, Jan. 19, 1959; Feb. 2, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Parade, June 5, 1949 (Box 55)
  - Park East, Apr. 1951 (Box 55)
  - Playbill- (Sam. S. Shubert Theatre), Feb. 16, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Playbill- (Ethel Barrymore Theatre), May 16, 1960 (Box 55)
  - Promenade, July, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Quick, Jan. 30, 1950; Mar. 26, 1951 (2) (Box 55)
  - Radio Album, Oct. 1949 (Box 55)
  - Radio Art, Sept. 15, 1933; July 1936 (Box 55)
  - Radio Best, Aug. 1949; Jan. 1950,; Oct. 1950 (Box 55)
  - Radio Daily, Sept. 21, 1943; Aug. 10, 1955 (Box 55)
  - Radio Digest, Mar. 1933 (Box 55)
  - Radio Guide, June 4, 1938; Oct. 22, 1938,; Nov. 17, 1939 (2) (Box 55)
  - Radio and Television Mirror, Aug. 1941 (2); Feb. 1942,; July 1949,; Oct. 1949,; Jan. 1950 (2),; May 1950,; Feb. 1956 (Box 55)
  - Radioland, Mar. 1934 (Box 55)
  - Radio Mirror, Aug. 1934 (Box 55)
  - Radio Parade, Jan. 1941 (Box 55)
  - Radio Review, Dec. 1944 (Box 55)
  - Radio Stars, Dec. 1935; Apr. 1938,; Apr. 1939 (Box 55)
  - Radio Television Mirror, Mar. 1951 (Box 55)
  - The Raster, summer issue 1954 (Box 55)
  - Recontructionist, Dec. 24, 1954 (Box 55)
  - Saturday Review, June 2, 1956 (2); Mar. 7, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Silver Screen, Feb. 1951 (Box 55)
  - Spectator, Aug. 1954 (Box 55)
  - Sponser, Oct. 8, 1951 (Box 55)
  - Table Talk, Jan. 13, 1936 (Box 55)
  - Telecast, Dec. 1949 (Box 55)
  - Telecasting, Nov. 28, 1949 (Box 55)
  - Televiewer, July 10, 1953 (Box 55)
  - Television Guide, Jan. 22, 1949; May 7, 1949,; Aug. 6, 1949,; Oct. 8, 1949,; Jan. 21, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Television News, Dec. 16, 1950; Feb. 24, 1951,; Mar. 17, 1951,; Apr. 7, 1951 (Box 55)
  - Television World (2), Feb. 20, 1949 (Box 55)
  - The Theatre, Apr. 1959; May 1959 (Box 55)
  - Theatre Arts, Sept. 1949; Oct. 1950 (Box 55)
  - This Month-in Television, May 1949 (Box 55)
  - Time, Apr. 26, 1943; Dec. 4, 1950,; Jan. 29, 1951 (2),; Mar. 2, 1959 (Box 56)
  - Today's Woman, Mar. 1951 (Box 56)
  - True Confessions, Jan. 1951 (Box 56)
  - Tune In, Mar. 1943; Nov. 1945 (Box 56)
  - T.V. and Radio Magazine, May 29, 1955; Oct. 9, 1955,; Jan. 22, 1956,; Sept. 2, 1956 (Box 56)
  - TV-Dial, Apr. 14, 1951; May 26, 1951,; June 9, 1951 (Box 56)
  - TV Digest, Nov. 19, 1949 (2); Apr. 29, 1950 (2),; June 3, 1950,; June 10, 1950 (2),; Nov. 11, 1950 (2),; Dec. 16, 1950,; Apr. 14, 1951 (2),; Apr. 19, 1952,; May 10, 1952,; June 28, 1952,; June 4, 1954 (2) (Box 56)
  - TV Family, Dec. 11, 1952 (Box 56)
  - TV Forecast, Dec. 30, 1950; Feb. 3, 1951 (2),; Feb. 10, 1951 (2),; Oct. 13, 1951,; Nov. 17, 1951,; Feb. 23, 1952,; Mar. 15, 1952,; Mar. 22, 1952 (2),; Apr. 12, 1952 (Box 56)
  - TV Guide, Apr. 8, 1950; Dec. 2, 1950 (2),; Mar. 3, 1951,; July 7, 1951,; Aug. 18, 1951,; Feb. 1, 1952 (2),; Feb. 22, 1952,; Feb. 29, 1952 (2),; Apr. 4, 1952,; Apr. 11, 1952,; Apr. 18, 1952,; Apr. 25, 1952,; May 2, 1952,; June 20, 1952,; June 27, 1952,; Sept. 5, 1952,; Oct. 10, 1952,; May 22, 1952,; July 24, 1953 (2),; July 31, 1953,; Aug. 7, 1953,; Aug. 21, 1953,; Sept. 18, 1953,; July 17, 1954,; Aug. 14, 1954,; Aug. 28, 1954,; Sept. 25, 1954,; Nov. 13, 1954,; Sept. 17, 1955,; Feb. 25, 1956,; Sept. 8, 1956,; Mar. 5, 19?? (Box 56)
  - TV News, June 4, 1954 (Box 56)
  - TV Post, Oct. 10, 1954 (Box 56)
  - TV Radio Mirror, Aug. 1954 (Box 56)
  - TV Review, May 19, 1951; Apr. 21, 1951,; June 16, 1951 (Box 56)
  - TV Screen, Feb. 1951 (2); Aug. 1951 (Box 56)
  - TV Show, May 1951 (2); Aug. 1951 (2),; May 1952,; Mid-Sept. 1952 (Box 56)
  - TV Today, Mar. 24, 1951 (Box 56)
  - TV Week, Feb. 16, 1952 (Box 56)
  - TV World, Feb. 1954 (Box 56)
  - Variety (Radio City Number), Dec. 20, 1932 (Oversize 17)
  - Westchester Life, May 1954 (Box 56)
  - Who's Who in Radio, Jan. 1936 (Box 56)
  - Who's Who in TV & Radio, 1951 (Box 56)
  - Who's Who on the Air, 1932 (Box 56)
  - Woman's Day, Nov. 1943; Dec. 1949,; June 1950,; Nov. 1950 (Box 56)
  - Woman's Home Companion (2), Sept. 1955 (Box 56)
  - Your Life, Aug. 1952 (Box 56)
  - Your Video Guide, May 12, 1951; Feb. 2, 1952 (Box 56)
  - Untranslated Japanese Magazine (Box 56)